Guide to the William S. Downing papers, 1922-2006.
Downing, William S. papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William S. Downing papers, 1922-2006.
6971
Downing, William S.,
309 cubic feet.
Correspondence, drawings, photographs, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of project files, correspondence, meeting notes, architectural drawings, specifications, photographs, photographic negatives, and slides related to Downing's architectural practice.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
William Smith Downing (1920-2011) was an architect and entrepreneur who spent most of his career working in Ithaca, New York. Downing was born in Orange, New Jersey and studied at the University of Virginia, graduating with a degree in architecture in 1946. During his early career, he practiced architecture in Charlottesville, Virginia and in New York City, where he worked for Skidmore, Owings, and Merrill and Edward Stone. After moving to Ithaca in 1959, Downing joined a local architectural firm and then established William Downing Associates. His firm was known for school additions, including Ithaca High School, as well as commercial buildings, including the Monarch Machine Tool Company located in Cortland, New York. In 1971, Downing purchased the former Ithaca junior high and high school, renovating the building into the DeWitt Mall, a successful example of adaptive reuse. The William S. Downing Prize was established at Cornell University in 1986 and is awarded annually in recognition of outstanding achievement in architectural design in the College of Architecture, Art, and Planning.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of project files, correspondence, meeting notes, architectural drawings, specifications, photographs, photographic negatives, and slides related to Downing's architectural practice. Also includes architectural drawings made by other Ithaca architects during the early 20th century.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Downing, William S., 1920-2011.; Downing, William S., 1920-2011.
Subjects:
Architecture -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Architecture -- United States -- History -- 21st century.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.) -- Architecture.
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Blueprints.; Photographs.; Negatives (photographic).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Cornell University building plans, specifications, and project files are restricted to permission of the office of Planning Design and Construction.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Office Records
Series II. Project Records
Series III: Specifications
Series IV: Photographic Materials
Series V: Drawings
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Office Records
  - Resumes (Box 1)
  - DBA Portfolio (Box 1)
  - Logo (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Hollister (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Malott (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Master Plan (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Tobin Field House (Box 1)
  - Cornell: G-Line Feasibility Study (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Registrar (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Multiple Housing (Box 1)
  - Cornell: CCC Counsel (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Renovating Suites (Box 1)
  - Cornell: Renovation and Redevelopment (Box 1)
  - Churches: First Church of Christ, Scientist (Box 1)
  - Churches: Belmont Baptist (Box 1)
  - Churches: Saint Catharine (Box 1)
  - Churches: Cherry Ave. Christian Church (Box 1)
  - Churches: Greek Orthodox Church (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Armory (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Buffalo Development (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Elmira Community Residence (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Divi Tower (Ramada) (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Drop In Center (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Gardner Real Estate Office (Box 1)
  - Commercial: Monarch (Box 1)
  - Competitions: Blacksburg Library (Box 1)
  - Competitions: Kansai Kah, Japan (Box 1)
  - Computer Graphics (Box 1)
  - Health Care: Health Care Industry (Box 1)
  - Health Care: Mental Health (Box 1)
  - Health Care: Lakeside (Box 1)
  - Parks and Recreation: Marinas (Box 1)
  - Residential: Residential Projects (Box 1)
  - Residential: E. Marshall (Box 1)
  - Residential: Gardner (Box 1)
  - Residential: Gifft (Box 1)
  - Residential: Walck (Box 1)
  - Restoration (Box 1)
  - Schools: Ithaca High School Master Plan (Box 1)
  - Schools: Tioga Central High School (Box 1)
  - Garages (folder empty) (Box 1)
  - Factories (Box 1)
  - Commercial Projects (Box 1)
  - Hospitality (Box 1)
  - Walmart (Box 1)
  - Ithaca Library (Box 1)
  - Solymar Beach (Box 1)
  - Misc. Brochure Material (Box 1)
  - Photos: Henry St. John Gym (Box 1)
  - Photos: Gardner (Box 1)
  - Photos: Monarch, Architectural Record Reprints (Box 1)
  - Photos: Edlund Presernation (Box 1)
  - Photos: Unmarked photographs and newspaper clippings for projects (Box 1)
  - Photos: Shephard Niles (Box 1)
  - Photos: Watkins Glen Swimming Pool (Box 1)
  - Photos: Crane & Hoist Corp. (Box 1)
  - Photos: Ramada Executive Tower (Box 1)
  - Photos: Armory (Box 1)
  - Photos: D.I.C.C. (Box 1)
  - Photos: Lakeside (Box 1)
  - Photos: Savings & Loan (Box 1)
  - Photos: Kaufmann Auditorium (Box 1)
  - Photos: TCTC Drive-In (Box 1)
  - Photos: Misc. (Box 1)
  - Photos: Gifft (Box 1)
  - Photos: Monarch: magazine clippings (Box 2)
  - Photos: Monarch (Box 2)
  - Photos: Moog (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: Owego (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: Marketing (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: Interviews (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: Tompkins County Foundation (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing:Ithaca School District (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: China (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: State University at Cortland (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: 1996-97, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Future Jobs/Marketing: K-Mart (Box 2)
  - Consultants (Box 2)
  - SCCSD (Box 2)
  - Verona (Box 2)
  - AIA Logo (Box 2)
  - New Covers (Box 2)
  - Recent Commissions (Box 2)
  - Firm Promotional Brochures (Box 2)
  - Collaborating Architects (Box 2)
  - Awards (Box 2)
  - Proposals: Water (Box 2)
  - Proposals: Armory Schematic Design (Box 2)
  - Proposals: Tompkins Mental Health Center (Box 2)
  - Proposals: Tompkins Mental Health Center Feasibility Study (Box 2)
  - Proposals: Leonardo & Wanzer Block Revitalization Feasibility Study (Box 2)
  - 254 - '86 (Standard Form Architect-Engineer and Related Services Questionnaires - 1986), 1986 (Box 2)
  - 254 - '87, 1987 (Box 2)
  - 254 (Various years) (Box 2)
  - 254 - '89-90, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - 255 (Standard Form Architect-Engineer Related Services for Specific Projects) (Box 2)
  - Consultants (Box 3)
  - Tranist Proposal (Box 3)
  - Misc. Brochure Sheets of Projects (Box 18)
  - Payroll checks (Box 51)
  - Appointment Books, 1962 (Box 51)
  - Appointment Books, 1963 (Box 51)
  - Payroll Books, 1958 (Box 51)
  - Payroll Books, 1963 (Box 51)
  - Payroll Books, 1965 (Box 51)
- Series II. Project Records
  - Numerical job lists, ca. 1959-2000, ca. 1959-2000 (Box 3)
  - Project Data (Box 3)
  - Ithaca High School, Ithaca, New York (Box 3)
  - The Wood Office (Box 3)
  - Country Club of Ithaca, Ithaca, New York, 1994 (Box 3)
    Project # 94-693
  - Greenport (Box 3)
  - Professional Registration - Letter from W. Downing to John, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Japan (Box 3)
  - B.I.D. (Ithaca Downtown Business Improvement District) (Box 3)
  - Current Projects, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (Box 3)
  - Hollister Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (Box 3)
  - G-Line (Box 3)
  - Moakley (Box 3)
  - Registrar's Office, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (Box 3)
  - Malott Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (Box 3)
  - Cornell University - Space Planning, Ithaca, New York (Box 3)
  - Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Montour House (Box 4)
  - Vineyard (Box 4)
  - Old Hundred - Classen, Ithaca, New York (Box 4)
  - Preservation Tax Incentives (Box 4)
  - Walck (Box 4)
  - Walck Residence - Public Relations (Box 4)
  - P.A. License (Box 4)
  - Lakeside (Box 4)
  - Lakeside (Box 5)
  - Lakeside (Box 6)
  - Ben Conger Inn, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Monarch Machine Tool Company - Project Data (Box 6)
  - Gardner (Box 6)
  - ICCC (Box 6)
  - Tompkins County Public Library, Ithaca, New York, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Ithaca Child Care Center, Ithaca, New York (Box 6)
  - State Education Department (Box 6)
  - Consultants (Box 6)
  - Contractors (Box 6)
  - Ithaca Drop-In Childcare Center, Ithaca, New York, 1994 (Box 6)
    Project # 94-689
  - Proposals (Box 6)
  - Elmira Community Residence, Elmira, New York (Box 6)
  - Salvation Army (Box 6)
  - Elmira, New York (Box 6)
  - Alcoholism Regulations (Box 6)
  - Regulations (Box 6)
  - Space OASAS Community Residence (Box 6)
  - Community Residence, Ithaca, New York (Box 6)
  - Human Services Coalition (Box 6)
  - DAAA-Willard (Box 6)
  - Willard (Box 6)
  - Ithaca Housing Authority (Box 6)
  - Youth Bureau (Box 6)
  - State Education Department (Box 6)
  - Phillips Library, Homer, New York (Box 6)
  - TCTC (Box 6)
  - Tompkins County Office Building (Box 6)
  - Town Hall, Town of Ithaca, New York (Box 7)
  - BOCES (Box 7)
  - DOT (Box 7)
  - Historic Preservation (Box 7)
  - Contract Conditions (Box 7)
  - Criteria (Box 7)
  - Armory (Box 7)
  - Division I - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 2 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - Concrete - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 4 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 5 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 6 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 7 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 8 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - Hardware - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - Glass - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 9 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - Carpet - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - 15 - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - Ground Source Heat Pumps (Box 7)
  - Geo-thermal (Box 7)
  - Radiant Heat (Box 7)
  - Sound Control (Box 7)
  - Specification Info (Box 7)
  - Security Devices (Box 7)
  - Marinas (Box 7)
  - Lansing, New York (Box 7)
  - Hospicare - Specifications (Box 7)
  - Community Performing Arts Center - Theatre (Box 8)
  - Community Performing Arts Center - Forum For the Arts (Box 8)
  - Adaptive Use (Box 8)
  - Corning YMCA, Corning, New York (Box 8)
  - Urban Planning (Box 8)
  - Urban Renewal (Box 8)
  - A General Plan: Ithaca, New York, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Ithaca, New York: A General Plan, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Market Potential for Downtown Ithaca, 1980 (Box 8)
  - West State Street Development Program, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Collegetown Development Program, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Moog - Art (Box 8)
  - Gallery 121 (Box 8)
  - Cottage Renovation, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Women's Community Building (Box 8)
  - Cornell University, New West Campus, Ithaca, New York (Box 8)
  - Unitarian Church, 1998 (Box 8)
  - United Methodist Church, Homer Ave. (Box 8)
  - United Methodist Church, Homer Ave. (Box 9)
  - Armory, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Alpha House, Trumansburg, New York (Box 9)
  - Day Care Centers (Box 9)
  - Tompkins County Public Library, Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - Trigager (Box 9)
  - Old Courthouse (Tompkins County Courthouse), Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - Tompkins County Courthouse Renovation, Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - St. Johns, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Lansing, New York (Box 9)
  - Lansing Fire Station, Lansing, New York (Box 9)
  - Mitchell Street (Box 9)
  - Mental Health Service Building (Box 9)
  - RHP Properties (Box 9)
  - Cornell University Feasibility Study - Admissions, Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - Cornell University Various Projects, Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - Cornell University COOP Nursery, Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - Cornell University Barnes Hall Feasibility Study, Ithaca, New York (Box 9)
  - Moog, Belize (Box 10)
  - Wiggins Development - La Tourelle, Ithaca, New York (Box 10)
  - Wiggins - L'Auberge, Ithaca, New York, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
  - Kazda (Box 10)
  - St. Catherine of Sienna (Box 10)
  - Odd Fellows (Box 10)
  - Tompkins County SPCA Feasibility Study and Schematic Design (Box 10)
  - Watson School of Engineering Program Study, SUNY Binghamton (Box 10)
  - Day Hall - Existing Furniture, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (Box 10)
  - Ithaca City Hall - Feasibility Study, Ithaca, New York (Box 10)
  - Moog, Inc., 1977 (Box 10)
  - A.A.U & Pools - Watkins Glen State Park Swimming Pool, Watkins Glen, New York (Box 10)
  - Next Step (Box 10)
  - Cranes, 1974 (Box 10)
    Project # 74-467
  - Cornell University, Ithaca, New York (Box 10)
  - Moog, 1986 (Box 10)
    Project # 86-613
  - TCAD (Tompkins County Area Development) Incubator Feasibility, 1987 (Box 10)
    Project # 87-620
  - TCAD (Tompkins County Area Development), Morse Chain, Feasibility Study (Box 10)
  - Post Office Redevelopment, 1986 (Box 10)
    Project # 86-612
  - Biggs (Box 10)
  - Ithaca Housing Authority RFP, Ithaca, New York (Box 10)
  - Black Oak Lane, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Ithaca Child Care Center, Ithaca, New York, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Ithaca Child Care Center, Ithaca, New York (Box 11)
  - Ithaca Child Care Center, Ithaca, New York (Box 12)
  - EPA Information on Asbestos (Box 12)
  - MVA, 1985 (Box 12)
    Project # 85-599
  - West Hill Development Project, Proposal, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Moog Space Products (Box 13)
  - Ciaschi (Box 13)
  - Ciaschi - Black Oak Lane (Box 13)
  - Ciaschi - College Avenue, Ithaca, New York (Box 13)
  - Ciaschi Building, Ithaca, New York, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Ciaschi - Strand Theatre, Ithaca, New York (Box 13)
  - White Contract (Box 13)
  - Cornell University Campus Planning Project, Ithaca, New York (Box 13)
  - Cabin Fever Festival (ICC) (Box 13)
  - Armory, Multiplier Calculation Forms (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Invoices, 1992 (Box 13)
  - Bay Horse Inn - Contract (Box 13)
  - Camel's Renovation - Invoice, 1992 (Box 13)
    Project # 92-670
  - Homer United Methodist Church - Correspondence and Invoice, Homer, New York (Box 13)
  - Advantage Auto - Invoice (Box 13)
  - Penn Yan Post Office, Invoice, Penn Yan, New York (Box 13)
  - White/Hranek Residence, Invoice, 1990 (Box 13)
    Project # 90-663
  - Turcotte Residence, Invoice, 1992 (Box 13)
    Project # 92-671
  - Armory (Box 13)
  - Mitchell Street (Box 13)
  - Macedon Day Care Center, 1995 (Box 13)
  - Various Projects - Cost Data Summary, 1960s (Box 13)
  - South Seneca Street, Ithaca, New York, 1995 (Box 13)
  - Bridges of Ithaca - Classen, Ithaca, New York, 1996 (Box 13)
  - Old Hundred - Classen, Ithaca, New York, 1996 (Box 13)
  - First Church of Christ, Scientist, 1997 (Box 13)
  - King Residence, 1996 (Box 13)
  - Ithaca City Hall Renovations, Ithaca, New York, 1998 (Box 13)
  - Freeville Community Residence, 1994 (Box 13)
    Project # 94-697
  - Hollister Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998 (Box 14)
  - Hollister Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998 (Box 15)
  - Schoellkopf Memorial Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Day Hall, Human Resources, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Malott Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1997 (Box 15)
  - Cornell University Golf Center, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998 (Box 15)
  - Schurman Hall, Ithaca, New York, 1999 (Box 15)
  - The Field House, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2000 (Box 15)
  - McConville Barn Pavilion, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999 (Box 15)
  - CCC University Counsel, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Wilson Lab, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Barnes Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Central Campus Space Planning, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Alpha House, Trumansburg, New York, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Montour Falls House, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Vineyard Residence, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Walck Residence, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Ithaca Community Child Care Center, Ithaca, New York, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Lakeside Nursing Home, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Drop-In Children's Center, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Tompkins County Public Library, Ithaca, New York, 1995 (Box 17)
  - Physicians Office Building II, 1999 (Box 17)
  - Dr. Cooley's Office, Oneida, New York, 2001 (Box 17)
  - Tompkins County Mental Health Services Building, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Ithaca Youth Bureau, Ithaca, New York, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Moog, Inc. Controls Group, 5 Year Facilities Plan, 1977-1982 (Box 18)
  - Turcotte Residence, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Lake Lauderdale State Park Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
  - 224 E. State Street Feasibility Study, Ithaca, New York (Box 18)
  - Titus Tower I C.I.A.P. Proposal (Box 18)
  - 411 Tioga Street, Ithaca, New York, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Newlin Residence, Brooktondale, New York, 1996 (Box 18)
  - J. Michael's Restaurant, Ithaca, New York, 1996 (Box 18)
  - East Hill School Condominiums, Ithaca, New York, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Halkiopoulos, Ithaca, New York, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Central Fire Station, Ithaca, New York - Ithaca Associated Architects, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Ithaca Downtown Development, Ithaca, New York, 1999, 2001 (Box 18)
  - William Downing Comments on Ithaca Commons, 1998-2000 (Box 18)
  - Town of Needham Master Plan, Needham, New York, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Stephen Palmer School Study, Needham, New York (Box 18)
  - Homer Folks Development Potential Study, Oneonta, New York, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Elmira Community Residence, Elmira, New York (Box 18)
  - Unidentified sketches (Box 27)
  - Cornell University Admissions Feasibility Study, Ithaca, New York, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Chamber of Commerce, Ithaca, New York, 1988 (Box 28)
    Project # 88-633
  - Chamber of Commerce, Ithaca, New York, 1988 (Box 29)
  - Monarch, 1979 (Box 29)
    Project # 79-511
  - Schoolhouse Manor, 1980 (Box 30)
    Project # 80-516
  - U.S. Post Office - Contract Documents, Construction Records, Design Submission Data, Correspondence, Ithaca, New York, 1964 (Box 31)
    Project # 336
  - Watkins Glen Pool, Watkins Glen, New York (Box 32)
  - Reconstruction Home, Ithaca, New York (Box 32)
  - Library, Ithaca, New York (Box 32)
  - First National Bank & Trust Company Remodeling, Ithaca, New York (Box 32)
  - Marathon Bus Garage, Marathon, New York, 1963 (Box 32)
  - Paleontological Research Institute, Ithaca, New York (Box 32)
  - First National Bank of Dryden, Dryden, New York (Box 32)
  - Ithaca Laundries Petrillose Cleaners, Ithaca, New York, 1962 (Box 32)
    Project # 62-180
  - Triangle Fraternity, 1961 (Box 32)
  - Triangle, Progressive Architecture Materials, 1962 (Box 32)
  - Cortland Hotel, 1963 (Box 32)
  - South Hill School - Shop Drawings, Specification Ditto Masters, Tracings 8 1/2 x 11" Sheets, Temperature Control Operating Instructions, Ithaca, New York (Box 33)
    Project # 241
  - Belle Sherman School Addition - Shop Drawings, Specification Ditto Masters, Tracings 8 1/2 x 11" Sheets, Temperature Control Operating Instructions, Ithaca, New York (Box 33)
    Project # 242
  - East Hill School Addition - Shop Drawings, Specification Ditto Masters, Tracings 8 1/2 x 11" Sheets, Temperature Control Operating Instructions, Ithaca, New York (Box 33)
    Project # 243
  - Daily Reports - Belle Sherman, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - Daily Reports - South Hill, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - Daily Reports - East Hill, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - Glen National Bank, Watkins Glen, New York (Box 34)
  - Tompkins County Trust Company Drive In Bank, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - Alpha Delta Phi, Shop Drawings (Box 34)
  - Poultry Building, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1965 (Box 34)
  - First Baptist Church, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - First Baptist Church, Owego, New York (Box 34)
  - Boynton Junior High School, Sound System (Box 34)
  - Board of Education - Contracts (Box 34)
  - Ithaca High School, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - City School District, Ithaca, New York (Box 34)
  - Finger Lakes Park Administration Building (Box 34)
  - Roy Park Library, 1964 (Box 34)
  - John Gauntlett Residence, 1964 (Box 34)
    Project # 372
  - Frances Gosh Residence, Ithaca, New York, 1962 (Box 34)
  - St. John's Church Ives House, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Clynes Residence, 1964 (Box 34)
  - Holt correspondence with Hazel Trefts (Box 34)
  - Tioga Center Schools, Tioga Center, New York (Box 34)
  - Tioga Elementary School, Tioga Center, New York (Box 35)
  - Tioga Central School, Tioga Center, New York (Box 35)
  - Nichols Elementary School (Box 35)
  - Ciaschi Building, Ithaca, New York, 1987 (Box 35)
    Project # 87-614
  - Ciaschi Building, Ithaca, New York, 1987 (Box 36)
  - Phi Gamma Delta Fraternity (Box 36)
  - Tompkins County Memorial Hospital - aka Biggs Memorial Hospital (Box 36)
  - Tompkins County Memorial Hospital - aka Biggs Memorial Hospital (Box 37)
  - Newark Valley School District Temporary School Building, 1966 (Box 37)
  - AOP (Alpha Omicron Pi), 1962 (Box 37)
  - Alpha Phi Sorority, Ithaca, New York - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1948 (Box 37)
  - Alpha Phi Specifications, Ithaca, New York - Holt & Downing, Architects (Box 37)
    Project # 252
  - Alpha Phi Sorority, Ithaca, New York - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Beta Sigma Rho - Certificates of Payment, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Glen Motor Court, Watkins Glen, New York, 1962 (Box 37)
    Project # 340
  - Langhams Residence, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Lehmer Apartment, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Staggs Residence - Porch Addition, Ithaca, New York, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Cayuga Lodge, 1961 (Box 37)
    Project # 305
  - Indelicato Apartment House (Box 37)
    Project # 314
  - Finger Lakes Auto Club, Montour Falls, New York, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Ithaca Savings and Loan Association, Ithaca, New York, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Ives House, 1960 (Box 37)
    Project # 307
  - Tioga Center Schools, Tioga Center, New York (Box 37)
  - Woodcock Apartment Building (Box 37)
  - J. Milton Cowan Residence, Ithaca, New York, 1959 (Box 37)
  - Roller Skating Rink - Warren W. Clute Memorial Park, Watkins Glen, New York, 1966 (Box 37)
  - W.W. Clute Residence - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1949 (Box 37)
  - Store Building for Paul Thayer, Ithaca, New York - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1948 (Box 37)
  - Jerome Thompson Residence, Elmira, New York - Holt, Architect, 1946 (Box 37)
  - Phi Epsilon Pi Fraternity, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1955 (Box 37)
  - Phi Epsilon Pi Fraternity - Specifications, Ithaca, NY - Holt, Architect (Box 37)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma Sorority, Ithaca, New York, 1958 (Box 37)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma - Specifications, Ithaca, New York (Box 37)
    Project # 272
  - Cortland Memorial Hospital, Cortland, New York - Holt, Architect, 1955 (Box 38)
  - Wilcox Press, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1945 (Box 38)
  - Specifications for MacDonald Residence, Kidders, New York - Holt & Gibb, Architects (Box 38)
  - Specifications for Cunningham Residence, Kidders, New York - Holt, Architect (Box 38)
  - Tioga County Ag Building, Owego, New York - Holt, Architect, 1945 (Box 38)
  - James W. Allen, Odessa, New York (Box 38)
  - A.T.O. (Box 38)
  - Marvin Bogema (Box 38)
  - Therm-Meter (Box 38)
  - Townsend Machine Tool Company, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect (Box 38)
  - W/O C. Geo.Wiedmaier - Holt, Architect, 1945 (Box 38)
  - W.A. Wimsatt Residence, Cayuga Heights, New York - Holt, Architect, 1945 (Box 38)
  - Gunsmith Lodge, C.V.P Young - Holt, Architect, 1946 (Box 38)
  - 515 Highland Ybor Geo. Sharpe, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1946 (Box 38)
  - Westview Terrace - Holt, Architect, 1940 (Box 38)
  - Cayuga Preventorium, Tompkins County, New York - Holt & Larkin, Architects, 1937 (Box 38)
  - Tompkins County Memorial Hospital - aka Biggs Memorial Hospital - Holt, Architect, 1956 (Box 38)
  - Unknown project (Box 38)
  - Mrs. V.S. Lawrence Residence, 1956 (Box 38)
  - Kappa Delta Sorority, Ithaca, New York, 1958 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous Notes & Data (Box 38)
  - St. John's Church - Specifications, Ithaca, New York, 1955 (Box 38)
  - Tom Speno (Box 38)
  - Dr. H.B. Sutton - Holt, Architect, 1957 (Box 38)
  - R.S. Stevens Residence - Holt, Architect, 1956 (Box 38)
  - Smidt, Seymour (Box 38)
  - Spencer School - Holt, Architect, 1955 (Box 38)